A man's reach should exceed his grasp... or what's a heaven for?
The Lost City of Z is a adventure, drama, history film directed by James Gray.
A true-life drama in the 1920s, centering on British explorer Col.
Percy Fawcett, who discovered evidence of a previously unknown, advanced
civilization in the Amazon and disappeared whilst searching for it.
Percival Fawcett, played by Charlie Hunnam.
Henry Costin, played by Robert Pattinson.
Nina Fawcett, played by Sienna Miller.
Jack Fawcett, played by Tom Holland.
James Murray, played by Angus Macfadyen.
Arthur Manley, played by Edward Ashley.
The Lost City of Z is a 2016 American epic biographical adventure drama film written and
directed by James Gray, based on the 2009 book of the same name by David Grann.
It portrays British explorer Percy Fawcett, who was sent to Brazil and made
several attempts to find a supposed ancient lost city in the Amazon.
It stars Charlie Hunnam as Fawcett; Robert Pattinson as his fellow explorer Henry Costin,
Sienna Miller as his wife, Nina Fawcett; and Tom Holland as his son, Jack.
Its world premiere was on October 15, 2016, as the
closing-night selection at the New York Film Festival.
It was released in the United States on April 14, 2017
by Amazon Studios and Bleecker Street.
It was praised by critics, but grossed only $19
million against a $30 million budget.
Despite its lack of financial success, Time magazine
listed it as one of its Top 10 Films of 2017.
"Z" is pronounced "zed", as spoken in the United
Kingdom, by the characters in the film.
It was pronounced "zee" by the British actors in the American
versions of promotional material to suit the local market.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
snake, world war i, river, expedition.
The tone is emotional.